FARNAZ TOWHIDI FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Toronto, Ontario, (506) 897-2353, farnaz.towhidi@gmail.com, Work Permit in Canada (PR) github.com/FarnazTowhidi | farnaztowhidi.com | Linkedin

HIGHLIGHTS

Full stack developer with years of experience in designing and developing user interface, testing, debugging, implementing components in amazing companies like IBM, Canadian Institute of Cyber Security and Biossentials. I always feel passionate about increasing the limits to academic knowledge thus my PHD and increasing the knowledge in General Assembly of Toronto.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Language, Frameworks, and Libraries: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, DOM, Bootstrap, React.js, Express,js, Node.js, Python, Django, Jira, Jenkins, TestRail, Eclipse, Selenium
- Database and DB Management Tools: MongoDB, SQL, mongoDB, Mongoose
- **Methodologies:** Object Oriented Programing, MVC pattern, Responsive Design, Oath Authentication, User stories, Wire framing, REST APIs, Deploy GitHub, Heroku, Git and Git Hub, Middleware, MERN Infrastructure, Agile Scrum
- Languages: English, Persian

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer

2021 - 2022

Iranian Iron & Steel Institute of Education (Remote), Tehran, Iran

- Implemented a website for workshops on Metallurgical and Materials engineering, designed and created ease of use in the scheduling and resourcing components for the company adding additional value and reducing complexity in client proves.
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, ASP Classic

Frontend Developer

2019

Canadian Institute of Cybersecurity, Fredericton, New Brunswick

- Designed and built website for International Conference on Privacy, Security and Trust, including information on events, workshops, organizers.
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, ASP Classic

Full Stack Developer

2009 - 2014

Biossentials, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Worked closely with a designer to create and deploy a new comprehensive layout that allowed the customers to easily connect with vital information
- Improved the quality of company search engine optimization performance. Overhauled the
 entire structure of the website, create keywords contents, change the naming of files and
 folder, recommended weekly content, deleting flash and other technologies to gain it
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, ASP Classic, SEO

Full Stack Developer

2005 - 2008

Maadiran, Tehran, Iran

■ Designed and modified dynamic web site for products automation, manufacturing, and after-sales support as a part of team of 4

- Analyzed user's needs and converted them to create right solutions, such as selecting products based on user's requirement
- Responsible for onboarding junior developers providing critical mentorship and training.
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Asp dot net, Microsoft SQL server

Full Stack Developer Parsportfolio, Tehran, Iran

2002 - 2005

- Part of a team of 7 to build stock trading website with monthly traffic of over 1 million visitors
- Contributed to coding applications for educational and salary portal using OOP
- Created the multimedia application, to help clients who wanted to learn stock exchange through application of pars portfolio. This multimedia was initially planed for only the clients of the company, however the success of the project led to the application becoming a product and allowed the company to create another source of revenue by selling it into the market.
- Technologies used: HTML, Asp dot net, Microsoft visual studio, Microsoft SQL server

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance (Contract)

2020

IBM, Fredericton, New Brunswick

- Part of security intelligence team of 10 working on QRadar that ensured the testing algorithms and probability threat analysis was maintained at peak efficiency
- Created and edited automated test cases, manual, automation and regression testing.
 Maintained the Knowledge on QRadar log and network activity and reports
- Technologies used: Selenium, QRadar, Eclipse, Test Rail, Git, Git Hub

PROJECTS BUILT THROUGH GENERAL ASSEMBLY

McDonald's Application

GitHub

- Solo, 1 week project for DRY REST API of fully-functional styled inventory application
- Technologies used: Express/Node and MongoDB, Python

Chatterbox GitHub

- Group of 4 developers creates a MERN stack application, a responsive single page application
- Uploader with the use of AWS S3 buckets and the npm package, "aws-sdk"
- Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, React, Socket.io, Amazon Web Services

Track Fit GitHub

- Group of 5 developers creates a full crud application in 1 week, for recording the user's daily fitness log
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Python, Django, PostreSQL

War Card Game GitHub

- Solo, 1 week project for the browser base game, using application state, manipulating DOM and includes shuffling and win/loss logic
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS and JavaScript

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive, General Assembly, Toronto, Canada, (GPA 3.98 of 4)	2022
PHD of Computer Science, UTM University, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia	2015
Master of Information Security, UTM University, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, (GPA 3.65 of 4)	2010